Guide to the Archives Union File (AUF), Section 7: Boxes 379-442
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 7: Boxes 379-442
Kheel Center for Labor- Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 7: Boxes 379-442
6046
Kheel Center
388.2 linear ft.
Pamphlets, publications.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
The Archives Union File is a collection of publications of United States labor unions. Included is information on the American Institute for Free Labor Development. The AUF collection consists largely of pamphlets and publications of unions, collected by the Kheel Center.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into twelve sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-63
Section 2: Boxes 64-126
Section 3: Boxes 127-191
Section 4: Boxes 192-256
Section 5: Boxes 257-319
Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
Section 7: Boxes 379-442
Section 8: Boxes 443-506
Section 9: Boxes 507-571
Section 10: Boxes 572-635
Section 11: Boxes 636-699
Section 12: Boxes 700-704
Boxes 650-659 and 661-662 have not been inventoried at this time.
SUBJECTS
Names:
AFL-CIO --Archives; AFL-CIO. American Institute for Free Labor Development--Archives; AFL-CIO. Building and Construction Trades Dept.--Archives; AFL-CIO. Department of Economic Research--Archives; AFL-CIO. Education Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Executive Council--Archives; AFL-CIO. Human Resources Development Institute--Archives; AFL-CIO. Industrial Union Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Legislative Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Public Employees Department--Archives; AFSCME --Archives; Air Line Pilots Association --Archives; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union --Archives; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Research Department--Archives; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America --Archives; American Association of University Professors --Archives; American Federation of Government Employees --Archives; American Federation of Labor --Archives; American Federation of Musicians --Archives; American Federation of Teachers --Archives; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists --Archives; American Guild of Musical Artists --Archives; American Postal Workers Union --Archives; Association of Flight Attendants (U.S.) --Archives; Bakery, Confectionary and Tobacco Workers International Union --Archives; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.) --Archives; Communication Workers Union --Archives; Communications Workers of America --Archives; Congress of Industrial Organizations --Archives; Federation of Westinghouse Independent Salaried Unions --Archives; Hotel & Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union --Archives; Illinois State AFL-CIO --Archives; Industrial Workers of the World --Archives; International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers --Archives; International Association of Fire Fighters --Archives; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers --Archives; International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades --Archives; International Brotherhood of Teamsters --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers Union --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. Educational Department--Archives; International Longshoremens and Warehousemens Union --Archives; International Typographical Union --Archives; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers --Archives; International Union of North American Laborers --Archives; International Union, Allied Industrial Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Ford Dept. --Archives; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers --Archives; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) --Archives; National Association of Postal Supervisors --Archives; National Maritime Union of America --Archives; National Writers Union (U.S.) --Archives; New York State AFL-CIO --Archives; New York State United Teachers --Archives; Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers International Union --Archives; Screen Actors Guild --Archives; Service Employees International Union --Archives; Sheet Metal Workers International Union --Archives; Teamsters for a Democratic Union --Archives; Textile Workers Union of America --Archives; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry --Archives; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America --Archives; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers --Archives; United Glass & Ceramic Workers of North America --Archives; United Mine Workers of America --Archives; United Office and Professionals Workers of America --Archives; United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum and Plastic Workers of America --Archives; United Steelworkers of America --Archives; Utility Workers Union of America --Archives; Writer's Guild of America --Archives
Subjects:
Agricultural laborers--Labor unions; Airlines--Employees--Labor unions; Textile workers--Labor unions; Barbers--Labor unions; Building-service employees--Labor unions; Clothing workers--Labor unions; Construction workers--Labor unions; Automobile industry workers--Labor unions; Bakery employees--Labor unions; Transport workers--Labor unions; Fire fighters--Labor unions; Electricians--Labor unions; Plumbers--Labor unions; Teachers--Labor unions; Glassworkers--Labor unions; Restaurants--Employees--Labor unions; Postal service--Employees--Labor unions; Rubber industry and trade--Labor unions
Form and Genre Terms:
Pamphlets.; Publications
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this collection:
6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 1: Boxes 1-63
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 2: Boxes 64-126
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 3: Boxes 127-191
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 4: Boxes 192-246
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 5: Boxes 257-319
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 8: Boxes 443-506
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 9: Boxes 507-571
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 10: Boxes 572-635
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 11: Boxes 636-699
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 12: Boxes 700-704
Boxes 650-659 and 661-662 have not been inventoried at this point.
Related Collections:
6046 mf: Archives Union File on Microfilm
CONTAINER LIST
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America (Box 379, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Away from the crowded city: a new concept in health care for union members., Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
    Notes: 2 copies
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Community meetings: a new approach to trade union political action; a grass-roots experiment conducted by Teamsters Local 688, St. Louis during November, 1951., Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
    Author: Local 688 (St. Louis, Missouri)
  - Item 3: The people must act, 1955; Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: 10 years of trade union Democracy in action: commemorating the 10th Anniversary of the Warehouse and Distribution Workers Union, Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Political Action Report to the 10th Annual City-Wide Shop Conference, Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Report of Oil workers Committee on Local 688's participation program, Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: A summary of wages and working conditions negotiated in Local 688 Contracts during 1951, Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Meet your union, Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Powerful Boss of St. Louis Teamsters is one of City's most controversial figures, Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
    Notes: Article
  - Item 10: A union's experiment in Health care, Publication (Box 379, Folder 1)
    Notes: Flyer
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 379, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 5, no. 1-4
  - Item 2: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 6, no. 1-5
  - Item 3: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 7, no. 1-5
  - Item 4: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 8, no. 1-5
  - Item 5: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 9, no. 1-5
  - Item 6: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 10, no. 1-2
  - Item 7: article - Union leader - and big business man, Publication (Box 379, Folder 2)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 379, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 1, no. 1, 4-8
  - Item 2: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 2, no. 2-14
  - Item 3: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 3, no. 1-3, 5-7, 14
  - Item 4: Local 584 News, Publication (Box 379, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 4, no. 1-6
- Milk Drivers and Dairy Employees Local Union No. 584, Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Medical costs upDental costs upTreatment costs upLaboratory costs up, Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
    Notes: Correspondence
  - Item 2: MDI opens additional locations, Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: The Financial squeeze, Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Important notice to all members of Local 584, Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Dear Member-We wish to stress the importance of an Annual Physical examination, Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Supplement and form #10 - The Kroger Grocery & Baking Company, Peoria, Illinois and Local Union No. 627 (Drivers and Warehouse Employes), Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Notice of Nomination for Officers and Business agents of Local 584, Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: Local 584 members and their families will be interested in these recent changes in Social Security Disability Benefits, Publication (Box 379, Folder 4)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 379, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: A review of the 1951 St. Louis Municipal Elections with special emphasis on the race for President of Board of Aldermen, Publication (Box 379, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Summary teamsters local 688's post election analysis, Publication (Box 379, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Report of Senator Robert Pentland and a general summary of Local 688's political education program during 1951, Publication (Box 379, Folder 5)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 379, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Independent survey made of quality of medical care at St. Louis labor health institute by two prominent medical authorities, Publication (Box 379, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: LHI an experiment in medical care, Publication (Box 379, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Statement of Solomon Barkin, Research Director, Textile Workers Union of America, Publication (Box 379, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Community Action, 1958; Publication (Box 379, Folder 6)
    Notes: January, 1958
  - Item 5: General survey of voting behavior in St. Louis and Missouri (1944-1950), Publication (Box 379, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: In defense of St. Louis Teamsters, Local Union no. 688, Publication (Box 379, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: Officers Report - to the 12th Annual City Wide Shop Conference, Publication (Box 379, Folder 6)
    Notes: 2nd copy
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 380, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Endorsement of President Truman - adopted by the Ninth annual city wide shop conference, Publication (Box 380, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Officers Report - to the 11th Annual City Wide Shop Conference, Publication (Box 380, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Between the lines by Harry B. Wilson, Publication (Box 380, Folder 1)
    Author: Harry B. Wilson
  - Item 4: A union's experiment in Health care, Publication (Box 380, Folder 1)
    Notes: Flyer. 2nd copy
  - Item 5: Planning for an integrated school system in St. Louis, Publication (Box 380, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Independent survey made of quality of medical care at St. Louis labor health institute by two prominent medical authorities, Publication (Box 380, Folder 1)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: A review of the 1951 St. Louis municipal elections with special emphasis on the race for President of Board of Aldermen, Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: A summary of wages and working conditions negotiated in Local 688 contracts during 1951, 1952; Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
    Notes: Reported to the ninth annual City-Wide Shop Conference, January 20, 1952. Prepared jointly by the Negotiations Department and Research Department, Warehouse and Distribution Workers Union Local 688, International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
  - Item 3: Planning for an integrated school system in St. Louis, 1951; Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
    Author: Warehouse and Distribution Workers Local 688. Committee on Democratic Rights of Members
    Notes: Prepared and presented by the Committee on Democratic Rights of Members, Warehouse and Distribution Workers Union, Local 688, Int'l Brotherhood of Teamsters.
  - Item 4: Community Action, Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
    Notes: number 2-3
  - Item 5: Wages and working conditions among St. Louis Warehousemen, Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Endorsement of President Truman - Adopted by the Ninth Annual City Wide, Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Community Action, Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
    Notes: number 1-5
  - Item 8: Wages and working conditions among St. Louis Warehousemen, Food Processing, and Clerical Employees as represented by Teamsters Local 688, Publication (Box 380, Folder 2)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Reaching the voter, the 1956 Pentland campaign, 1957; Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
    Notes: Report to the 14th annual city-wide shop conference, Teamsters local 688, Jan. 27, 1957.
  - Item 2: Wages and working conditions among St. Louis Warehousemen (serial), Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: The Everyday Magazine, 1952; Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
    Notes: 30 March 1952.
  - Item 4: LHI an experiment in medical care, Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Officers report - Local No. 688 to the Ninth Annual City-Wide Shop Conference, Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Declaration of trust, Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: A union's in health care, Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: Political Action Report to the 10th Annual City-Wide Shop Conference, Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: Resolutions Committee Report, Publication (Box 380, Folder 3)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 380, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Reaching the voter, the 1956 Pentland campaign, 1957; Publication (Box 380, Folder 4)
    Notes: Report to the 14th annual city-wide shop conference, Teamsters local 688, Jan. 27, 1957. 2nd copy
  - Item 2: Community Action, 1958; Publication (Box 380, Folder 4)
    Notes: Jan. 1958. 2nd copy
  - Item 3: St. Louis Post-Dispatch: A St. Louis Union, Publication (Box 380, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Meet Harold J. Gibbons: powerful boss of St. Louis Teamsters is one of City's most controversial figures, Publication (Box 380, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Pension plan, Publication (Box 380, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Pension fund of the, Publication (Box 380, Folder 4)
    Author: Local 807
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 380, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Wages and working conditions among St. Louis Warehousemen., 1955-1959 (Box 380, Folder 5)
    Notes: 1955, 1957-1959
  - Item 2: America has adopted an eleventh cammandment"Thou shalt not be accused", Harold J. Gibbons, Publication (Box 380, Folder 5)
    Notes: Press release
  - Item 3: Annual Report - 1958, Publication (Box 380, Folder 5)
- Unity Welfare Association, Publication (Box 380, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: How community action succeeds in St. Louis: a report from Local 688, Publication (Box 380, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: 6th Annual Meeting, Publication (Box 380, Folder 6)
- Flyers, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Ammunition, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
    Notes: Vol. 1, no. 1, 4-9
  - Item 2: Mail Order Mirror, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
    Notes: vol. 1, no. 6
  - Item 3: 743 Successful in election bid for retail stores, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Prestige won't cushion the fall!, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Rules of the secret ballot election, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Company Agrees: consent election to be held Jan. 15, 1954, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Sent home early without notice? Or a guaranteed 40 hours?, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: You can't winNOT while the company is doing ALL the manipulating!, Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Job security: guaranteed by a union contract..., Publication (Box 381, Folder 1)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 381, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: St. Louis Post-Dispatch, 1962; Publication (Box 381, Folder 2)
    Notes: Sunday July 8, 1962. 2 copies
  - Item 2: Labor World, 1961; Publication (Box 381, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 19, no.7-8 (1961)
  - Item 3: Labor World, 1963; Publication (Box 381, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 20, no. 16-17 (1963)
  - Item 4: Pioneers in Union Race Relations: New Citizen, Publication (Box 381, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 1, no. 29
  - Item 5: Teamster's Local 688 Health & Medical Camp, Publication (Box 381, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Annual Report (Teamsters Local 688 Health and Medical Camp), Publication (Box 381, Folder 2)
- The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 7, no. 1-12
  - Item 2: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 8, no. 1-3, 5-12
  - Item 3: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 9, no. -12
  - Item 4: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 10, no. 2-12
  - Item 5: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 3)
    Notes: vol. 11, no. 2-6
- The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 4)
    Notes: vol. 11, no. 7-12
  - Item 2: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 4)
    Notes: vol. 12, no. 1-9, 11-12
  - Item 3: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 4)
    Notes: vol. 13, no. 1-12
  - Item 4: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 4)
    Notes: vol. 14, no. 1-12
- The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 5)
    Notes: vol. 15, no. 1-12
  - Item 2: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 5)
    Notes: vol. 17, no. 1-5, 7-9, 11-12
  - Item 3: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 5)
    Notes: vol. 18, no. 1-12
  - Item 4: The 816 Express, Publication (Box 381, Folder 5)
    Notes: vol. 19, no. 2-4, 9
  - Item 5: Report (Favorable) on a teamsters Local by A.H. Raskin, Publication (Box 381, Folder 5)
    Author: A. H. Raskin
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Address of Dave Beck, general president, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, at the closing session of the First Annual meeting of the Central States Conference of Teamsters, Chicago, Illinois, April 26, 1954, Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
    Author: Dave Beck
  - Item 2: Beck reports on Europe, Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Dangerous combination, Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
    Author: International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
  - Item 4: Labor and international relations, 1932; Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
    Author: Daniel J. Tobin
  - Item 5: Life, accident and health insurance plan, 1956; Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
    Notes: Michigan Conference of Teamsters Welfare Fund, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America, A.F. of L.-C.I.O.
  - Item 6: Report of the Appeals Committee on the appeal of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Roster of Local Unions, Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Your community and., Publication (Box 382, Folder 1)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Agreement between and Amalgamate Meat Cutters and Butcher Workment of North America, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: We are happy to advise that on Sept. 24, 1954, the International Brotherhood and the Amalgamated. Entered into an agreement which we know will be lasting and beneficial to the membership of our respective international unions., Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Hard facts tell the story: why teamsters are under attack, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Report from Washington, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 2, no. 1, 4-5
  - Item 5: Report from Washington, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 3, no. 1-11
  - Item 6: Report from Washington, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
    Notes: vol. 4, no. 1-2
  - Item 7: What proposed labor legislation would do to unions, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Attachment A - Automation and employment trends in trucking, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Attachment B - Automation and employment trends in the fruit and vegetable canning industry, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: Attachment C - Automation and employment trends in the Dairy Industry, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: Teamster wage gains top others, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: Teamsters News Service - Biography of James R. Hoffa, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 13: Hard facts tell the story: why teamsters are under attack, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
  - Item 14: Dave Beck comes out of the West, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
    Author: Joe Miller
  - Item 15: Report of General President Dave Beck, Publication (Box 382, Folder 2)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Publication (Box 382, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: From the Office of Public Relations"Enclosed is a copy of The Issue" - 1955, Publication (Box 382, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Railroad opposition has been cited by John Reddingas responsible for preventing the Post Office from realizing an annual $600,000 saving in handling mail to and from New Jersey, Publication (Box 382, Folder 3)
    Author: Teamsters News Service